Annapa Reddy Koushik Reddy

akoushikreddy98@gmail.com | 475-276-4303 | portfolio website

Stamford, CT,06906 <u>LinkedIn</u>

Graduate Student at University of Connecticut

Master's student at the University of Connecticut majoring in Business Analytics and Project Management with a minor in Data Science. Previously worked at FactSet Research Systems Inc's Content Engineering Department, where I have solved various client queries and worked with stakeholders. Experienced in Data Analytics, Visualization and Machine Learning, interned as Data Scientist.

Education

University of Connecticut, USA.

MS in Business Analytics and Project Management, Expected Graduation Year 2024

GITAM University, India

BTech in Computer Science, Graduation Year 2020

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python | JavaScript | R | Java | C | C# | C++ | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap **Libraries**: Django | NumPy | Pandas | Matplotlib | Seaborn | Sci-Kit Learn | Keras | TensorFlow

Database: MySQL | PostgreSQL | SQLite

Others: Statistics | JMP | Data Structures | Algorithms | Machine Learning

Work Experience

FactSet Research Systems Inc, Hyderabad | Software Engineer | 03/2021 - 06/2022

- Executed On-call Engineering responsibilities. Maintained client feeds and participated in Stakeholder meetings.
- Engineered content pipeline through optimization by transforming data architecture.
- Upgraded applications and data feeds with Python and C#.
- Formulated content pipeline in AWS cloud to boost the performance by more than 50%.

Kenexoft Technologies, Hyderabad | Software Engineer Intern | 08/2020 – 10/2020

- Managed a group of interns as Team Lead for AIRES project, which assists in hiring employees.
- Developed an NLP model with text vectorization techniques, which reduces the effort to search for a required candidate by 25%.
- Integrated an interface to NLP model with python application.
- Presented a demo to client, in flask environment.

Fountane Labs, Hyderabad | Data Science Intern | 05/2019 – 06/2019

- Visualized and Cleaned eye patient's data obtained from Kumbh mela (Indian festival).
- Built supervised machine learning model to predict diagnosis of an eye patient with an accuracy of 82%.
- Accelerated retrieval of patient's information by 4 times by building a chatbot and integrating it into the client's website

Projects

NBA Analysis and Prediction:

- Aggregated and prepped 21 years of MVP votes, players and team's data from basketball-reference using Beautiful Soup and selenium in python.
- Predicted top 5 MVP players with Random Forest model for the next consecutive years.
- Obtained an accuracy of 88% using a custom error metric which improves the model performance.

Attendance Using Face Recognition

- Image recognition Model in python which can be used to mark attendance without human effort in schools and organization.
- Model detects and captures faces from Images with OpenCV in python and haarcascade xml model.
- Built a classification model on top of existing Facenet Model in Keras, obtained an accuracy of 88.4%.

Safe Home Surveillance:

- Developed a Diango application, to facilitate user accounts with login feature, modeled with SQLite database.
- Used to manage, track and report Security System in Households.
- Applied Django ORM techniques and integrated Django-Middleware for website security.

Pygames With Python:

Redesigned AlienInvasion game with PyGames Library.